# Ronan Sprake

19 Collingwood Close, Norwich, NR9 3QE 07944 277678 / ronansprake@gmail.com

## **Profile**

I'm a self-motivated UX Designer with extensive in-house, agency and start-up experience. I build inclusive customer experiences with User Centred Design practices, delivering creative, sustainable solutions while remaining business focused and value driven.

My portfolio: https://ronansprake.co.uk/portfolio-rsprake.pdf

# **Key Skills & Attributes**

- Multi-skilled interaction designer with a focus on usability, accessibility and team collaboration
- Skilled with design tools including Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD / CC, Axure, Invision and Zeplin
- Experienced in user testing and research methodologies (qualitative and quantitative)
- A practical and positive approach to strategic change and evolving requirements
- Encouraging transparency, trust, open and candid feedback to challenge thinking at all stages

## **Employment History**

#### Upside Money (Techstars '21) Lead UX Designer

March 2021 - Present

I joined an early stage startup to experience a Techstars Future of Finance Accelerator. I progressed the research and design of innovative products based on Open Banking technology and Big Data insights.

- Executed the research and UX design of customer experiences across D2C and B2B iOS and Web products, representing the voice of the customer at all stages
- Uncovered and iteratively solved iOS onboarding issues, reducing failure demand
- Introduced Lean UX practices to enable rapid collaboration with distributed team members
- Established Design System foundations to introduce consistency and accessibility standards
- Collaborated with Sales to design a proposition testing framework, interviewing retailers to understand pain points and product design opportunities
- Built strong relationships with the engineering team, ensuring user stories are clearly understood and that design and development work hand-in-hand to achieve the best customer outcomes

#### Aviva

### **Senior UX Designer**

March 2017 - March 2021

Designing complex customer journeys across Aviva's digital estate including major parts of the Global Design System, enhancing experiences for over 31 million customers worldwide.

- Principal UX on Aviva's <u>Framework Design System</u>, used by 120 designers in 9 countries. I
  contributed designs while managing backlog for 2 UX designers, providing priorities and direction
- Produced journey maps, sketches, wireframes and interactive prototypes for a variety of products, including quote & payment, car & home insurance, claims, investments and operations
- Increased cross-discipline collaboration, leading to a ~50% increase in my team's sprint velocity
- Presented at Accessibility Champions Group sessions, promoting WCAG standards across Digital

- Received personal feedback from the Head of UX: "It's the best piece of design we've done since I've been at Aviva. It's a beacon that leads the way into a brighter, better future"
- Frequently gave presentations at monthly design meetings, hosted in Hoxton (80 UX/UI designers)
- Presented actionable heuristic reviews for strategic partnerships (Barclays, HSBC and Santander)
- Interviewed and mentored designers, giving talks to groups of college and university students

### Soak (digital agency) UX Manager

Jul 2015 - Mar 2017

Realising my strength and passion was for UX design, I worked with global brands including Red Bull, GE, The Economist and Games Workshop. See <u>soak.co.uk</u>.

- Recruited, managed and mentored 2 UX designers and 2 UI developers
- Organised and led design workshops, lab and guerrilla testing
- Delivered successful design pitches (London, Paris, Salzburg)

Soak Lead UI Developer

Jan 2012 - Jul 2015

Led creative product builds using Angular and React for clients including HSBC, IBM and Adnams.

Soak UI Developer

Jan 2009 - Jan 2012

The first employee of a highly successful agency, I built design systems and emails for GE and Nissan.

**Digital Overload** 

**Full Stack Developer** 

Nov 2007 - Jan 2009

A digital agency, I built digital products while training in Git, HTML, CSS, JS, PHP and MySQL.

Permastore IT Technician

Oct 2005 - Nov 2007

Managed critical infrastructure, I also designed custom touchscreen and barcode interfaces.

## **Education**

Aviva	Aviva Certificate in General Insurance	2018
Open University	Certificate in Web Applications Development (Distinction)	2006 – 2008
University of Lancaster	History BA (Hons), (2:1)	2002 - 2005

### **Interests**

My favourite things include cinema, cooking, music and spending time with my family.

#### References available upon request